<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oleng</title>
    <link>https://oleng.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on oleng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 09:05:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://oleng.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker tips</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/2020/01/04/docker-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 09:05:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/2020/01/04/docker-tips/</guid>
      <description>Some useful tips for docker
  Making shortcuts for useful commands (with flags) to free up space is one time effort compared to remembering which command Docker provides. Use alias on macOS and put them in ~/.bash_profile so they&#39;re loaded in your terminal (I use ~/.bashrc for aliases holder, which needs to be sourced unlike .bash_profile, see my .dev/dotfiles repo for more info). Alias is auto completed in bash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User security: short guide</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/2020/01/01/user-security-short-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 12:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/2020/01/01/user-security-short-guide/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimers: This is not a comprehensive list. Complete security practice includes everything from user actions, hardwares, network, softwares, attack theories &amp;amp; methods, time frame period &amp;amp;etc, in other word NOT short or simple.
I am not a professional security, do not trust easily. AFAIK as of today these are valid, re-evaluation in the future is necessary. Critiques, inputs and questions are welcome.
 Rule of thumbs on improving online security (authentication, more security than privacy) for common users:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t make your kids learn programming</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/28/dont-make-your-kids-learn-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 16:23:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/28/dont-make-your-kids-learn-programming/</guid>
      <description>Ok, I admit that&#39;s click-baity.
What I meant is, don&#39;t push your children to learn programming for your sake, by your way. Especially if you don&#39;t know much or even anything about it.
I too don&#39;t know anything about guiding or teaching kids. But there are two suggestions that I don&#39;t think can&#39;t be wrong:
  If you can, find out if they have interest in computer hardwares, Raspberry Pi is very capable &amp;amp; affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>$ whoami I was a Digital Imaging Technician (DIT) for a motion picture production company, became a Post-Production engineer slash Post-Production supervisor since end of 2009. I&#39;ve designed, budgeted, processed purchases, as well as built and maintained a few visual post-production facility companies in Jakarta. Read a brief explanation about it here. Most of the companies I worked with were working on TV commercials on daily basis. I was also directly involved in several Indonesian movie titles, such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-production facility considerations</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/26/post-production-facility-considerations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 19:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/26/post-production-facility-considerations/</guid>
      <description>Key points when considering to build a post-production facility:
  Designing system for the entire facility: What is the medium &amp;amp; viewing target that company provides services for?
The answer to this question determines the kind of system a facility needs. As a general rule of thumb if a facility needs to facilitate the top two kinds of the production types 1, then we&#39;ll be talking about medium to large facility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why blogging?</title>
      <link>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/24/why-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 16:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://oleng.github.io/2019/12/24/why-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m blogging again. I don&#39;t think geocities still exists today, and the perception of what blogging means has changed a few times over. I&#39;m quite certain there&#39;s only maybe 1 in 200-500 chance you&#39;ll meet someone who knows what blog stands for, or what that meant originally.
The term blog was short for weblog. It&#39;s a log, on the web. Not a marketing page or online diary. Back then blogging was an exclusive domain of nerds; hackers, webmasters &amp;amp; sysadmins.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>